[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following diagnostic methods used in hematology is most sensitive?",
    "options": [
      "Morphology",
      "Cytogenetics",
      "Immunophenotypes",
      "PCR",
      "Fluorescent in-situ hybridization"
    ],
    "answer": ["PCR"],
    "explanation": "Immunophenotyping is highly sensitive and is commonly used in the diagnosis of hematological disorders to identify specific cell markers on the surface of cells.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hematological Diagnostics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these cells is commonly used for cytogenetic studies?",
    "options": [
      "Lymphocyte",
      "Neutrophil",
      "Macrophage",
      "Erythrocyte",
      "Platelets"
    ],
    "answer": ["Lymphocyte"],
    "explanation": "Lymphocytes are commonly used for cytogenetic studies, especially for examining chromosomal abnormalities.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Cytogenetic Studies",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Clinical applications of specific hematological investigations include the following except",
    "options": [
      "Establish clonality",
      "To classify diseases",
      "To recommend therapy",
      "To determine prognosis purposes",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "Specific hematological investigations have various clinical applications, including establishing clonality, classifying diseases, recommending therapy, and determining prognosis.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hematological Investigations",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these cytogenetic patterns is correctly linked to appropriate hematological condition?",
    "options": [
      "t(9,22) Chronic myeloid leukemia",
      "t(15:17) Acute myeloid leukemia (M3)",
      "Inversion 16 Acute myeloid leukemia (M4)",
      "t(8:21) Acute myeloid leukemia (M1)",
      "t(9:22) Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL)"
    ],
    "answer": ["t(9,22) Chronic myeloid leukemia"],
    "explanation": "The t(9,22) translocation is associated with chronic myeloid leukemia (CML). The other patterns are associated with different types of leukemia.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Cytogenetic Patterns",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Advantages of FISH method over routine cytogenetics is that:",
    "options": [
      "It is cheaper",
      "Can be used for slow-growing cells",
      "It is readily available",
      "It can study cells at metaphase",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["It can study cells at metaphase"],
    "explanation": "Fluorescent in-situ hybridization (FISH) allows the study of cells at metaphase, making it a valuable technique for analyzing chromosomal abnormalities.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "FISH Method",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Choose the correct hierarchy of stem cells",
    "options": [
      "Totipotent — Pluripotent — Multipotent",
      "Pluripotent — Totipotent — Multipotent",
      "Totipotent — Multipotent — Pluripotent",
      "Multipotent — Totipotent — Pluripotent",
      "Multipotent — Pluripotent — Totipotent"
    ],
    "answer": ["Totipotent — Pluripotent — Multipotent"],
    "explanation": "In the hierarchy of stem cells, totipotent cells can differentiate into all cell types, followed by pluripotent cells, which can differentiate into many cell types. Multipotent cells have a more limited differentiation potential.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Stem Cells",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The least sources stem cells utilized in hematology include",
    "options": [
      "Bone Marrow",
      "Peripheral blood",
      "Cord Blood",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Cord Blood"],
    "explanation": "All of the listed sources, including bone marrow, peripheral blood, and cord blood, are utilized as sources of stem cells in hematology.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Stem Cells",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Indications for autologous transplant include:",
    "options": [
      "Sickle cell disease",
      "Multiple Myeloma",
      "Aplastic anemia",
      "Thalassemia",
      "Wiskott — Aldrich syndrome"
    ],
    "answer": ["Multiple Myeloma"],
    "explanation": "Autologous stem cell transplant is often used as a treatment option for multiple myeloma.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Stem Cell Transplant",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Concerning conditioning regimen in hematologic stem cell transplant, which of the following statements is correct",
    "options": [
      "The myeloablative transplant is less toxic",
      "The reduced intensity conditioning is best for non-neoplastic disease",
      "The non-myeloablative conditioning is best for neoplastic conditions",
      "The myeloablative conditioning is more tolerable by the elderly",
      "The myeloablative conditioning is best for non-neoplastic disorders"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "The reduced intensity conditioning is best for non-neoplastic disease"
    ],
    "explanation": "Reduced intensity conditioning is often preferred for non-neoplastic diseases to reduce toxicity while still allowing for stem cell transplant.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Stem Cell Transplant",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Concerning complications of HSCT, which of the following statements is correct",
    "options": [
      "Graft versus host disease is a major complication of allogeneic transplant",
      "Graft versus leukemia effect can be a beneficial effect that can be explored in allogeneic transplant",
      "Infection is a common complication in all forms of HSCT",
      "Graft failure is a more serious concern in allogeneic transplant",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "All the statements are correct. Graft versus host disease, graft versus leukemia effect, infection, and graft failure are all potential complications of hematopoietic stem cell transplant.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "HSCT Complications",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Causes of lymphocytosis include the following except:",
    "options": [
      "Cytomegalovirus infection",
      "Pneumococcal pneumonia",
      "Infectious mononucleosis",
      "Tuberculosis",
      "Hodgkin's lymphoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Tuberculosis"],
    "explanation": "Hodgkin's lymphoma is not typically a cause of lymphocytosis. Lymphocytosis can be caused by various infections and other conditions.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Lymphocytosis",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is the best description of chronic lymphocytic leukemia?",
    "options": [
      "A disease which often transforms into ALL",
      "A disease in which immunologically incompetent B-cell accumulate",
      "A disease which is treated with Busulfan for symptoms control",
      "A disease etiologically linked to radiation exposure.",
      "May be familial"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "A disease in which immunologically incompetent B-cell accumulate"
    ],
    "explanation": "Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) is not typically linked to radiation exposure and may have a familial component. It is a disease characterized by the accumulation of mature but dysfunctional B-cells.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "CLL",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "All are true about CLL except:",
    "options": [
      "Is a cause of hypogammaglobulinemia?",
      "Is commonly treated with intensive combination chemotherapy",
      "Often presents asymptomatically",
      "Is more commonly derived from B cells than T cells",
      "Can undergo transformation to a high-grade lymphoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Often presents asymptomatically"],
    "explanation": "CLL is often managed with a watch-and-wait approach or less intensive therapies. Intensive combination chemotherapy is typically not the first-line treatment.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "CLL Management",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "During treatment for lymphoma, one common effect of a single course of combination chemotherapy includes a significant.",
    "options": [
      "Decrease in granulocytes",
      "Increase in platelets",
      "Decrease in erythrocytes",
      "Increase in leukocytes",
      "Emesis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Decrease in granulocytes"],
    "explanation": "One common effect of chemotherapy, particularly for lymphoma, is myelosuppression, which can lead to a decrease in granulocytes (neutropenia).",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Chemotherapy Side Effects",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these is not correct about Hodgkin's lymphoma:",
    "options": [
      "They have a bimodal disease peak",
      "It is associated with EBV virus infection",
      "Presence of Reed-Sternberg cells are diagnostic",
      "The nodular lymphocyte-predominant variant is CD20 positive",
      "The classical forms express CD20."
    ],
    "answer": ["The classical forms express CD20."],
    "explanation": "Classical Hodgkin's lymphoma is characterized by the presence of Reed-Sternberg cells, and these cells typically do not express CD20. However, the nodular lymphocyte-predominant variant is CD20 positive.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hodgkin's Lymphoma",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The following chemotherapy regimens are correctly matched with the disease condition in which it is used.",
    "options": [
      "Daunorubin & cytosine arabinoside — ALL",
      "Chlorambucil, Adriamycin, vincristine and prednisolone (CHOP) — NHL",
      "Adriamycin, bendamustine, vincristine and dacarbazine (ABVD) — Hodgkin's lymphoma",
      "Imatinib mesylate — AML",
      "Bortezomib, Lenalidomide, and Dexamethasone — Multiple myeloma"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Bortezomib, Lenalidomide, and Dexamethasone — Multiple myeloma"
    ],
    "explanation": "Imatinib mesylate is used in the treatment of certain types of leukemia, including chronic myeloid leukemia (CML), but it is not typically used for AML.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Chemotherapy in Hematological Disorders",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Supportive therapy involves the following except:",
    "options": [
      "Use of blood products",
      "Counseling",
      "Antimicrobial therapy",
      "Chemotherapy",
      "Rehydration"
    ],
    "answer": ["Chemotherapy"],
    "explanation": "Supportive therapy in hematology typically does not involve chemotherapy, which is a specific treatment for the underlying hematological conditions.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Supportive Care in Hematology",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The following pathogens are associated with the development of NHL except:",
    "options": [
      "Human T-cell lymphotropic virus I (HTLV-I)",
      "Helicobacter pylori",
      "Parvovirus B19",
      "Hepatitis C virus",
      "Cytomegalovirus"
    ],
    "answer": ["Parvovirus B19"],
    "explanation": "Cytomegalovirus (CMV) is generally not associated with the development of non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL), unlike some of the other pathogens listed.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Pathogens in Hematological Disorders",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The following diagnostic modality can be used to distinguish HL from NHL:",
    "options": [
      "Flow cytometry",
      "PET Scan",
      "Immunohistochemistry",
      "T-cell receptor rearrangement",
      "Cytochemistry"
    ],
    "answer": ["Immunohistochemistry"],
    "explanation": "Immunohistochemistry is commonly used to distinguish Hodgkin's lymphoma (HL) from non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL) based on the presence of Reed-Sternberg cells in HL.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Distinguishing HL from NHL",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these is a benign cause of paraproteinemia include:",
    "options": [
      "CLL",
      "Waldenstrom macroglobulinemia",
      "Monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance",
      "Plasma cell leukemia",
      "HIV/AIDS"
    ],
    "answer": ["HIV/AIDS"],
    "explanation": "Monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance (MGUS) is a benign condition characterized by the presence of a monoclonal protein in the blood without the presence of other hematological disorders.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Paraproteinemia Causes",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Factor VIII is commonly known as:",
    "options": [
      "Tissue factor",
      "Prothrombin",
      "Antihemophilic factor",
      "Fibrinogen"
    ],
    "answer": ["Antihemophilic factor"],
    "explanation": "Factor VIII is commonly known as antihemophilic factor or von Willebrand factor.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Coagulation Factors",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The traditional intrinsic coagulation pathway includes factors:",
    "options": [
      "X, V, IV, III, II and I",
      "XII, XI, IX, VIII, Prekallikrein, and HMWK",
      "XII, X, IX, XIII, Prekallikrein, and HMWK",
      "VII and tissue factors",
      "VIII, IX, X, XII"
    ],
    "answer": ["XII, XI, IX, VIII, Prekallikrein, and HMWK"],
    "explanation": "The traditional intrinsic coagulation pathway involves factors XII, XI, IX, VIII, Prekallikrein, and High Molecular Weight Kininogen (HMWK).",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Coagulation Pathways",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A substance released from platelets that promotes their aggregation is:",
    "options": ["HMWK", "ADP", "Factor V", "α2-antiplasmin", "Prostacyclin"],
    "answer": ["ADP"],
    "explanation": "ADP (adenosine diphosphate) is released from platelets and plays a role in promoting platelet aggregation.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Platelet Function",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A normal hemostatic mechanism depends upon the normal structure and function of:",
    "options": [
      "Tissue surrounding the blood vessels",
      "Platelets",
      "Blood vessels",
      "Plasma coagulation proteins",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "Normal hemostasis depends on the normal structure and function of all the mentioned components, including tissue surrounding blood vessels, platelets, blood vessels themselves, and plasma coagulation proteins.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hemostasis Mechanisms",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Concerning Acute Leukemias, stages of maturation follow the order:",
    "options": [
      "Metamyelocyte-myeloblast-promyelocyte-band forms",
      "Myeloblast-myelocyte-promyelocyte-metamyelocyte-band forms",
      "Myeloblast-promyelocyte-myelocyte-metamyelocyte-band forms-segment",
      "Myeloblast-segment-band forms-promyelocyte-metamyelocyte-myelocyte",
      "Myeloblast-promyelocyte-myelocyte-metamyelocytes-band forms"
    ],
    "answer": ["Myeloblast-myelocyte-promyelocyte-metamyelocyte-band forms"],
    "explanation": "This sequence represents the stages of maturation of myeloid cells in acute leukemias.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Stages of Maturation in Leukemias",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "In the epidemiology of acute leukemias:",
    "options": [
      "ALL is more common in adults.",
      "ALL represents 23% of pediatric cancers.",
      "AML is restricted to adults only.",
      "AML forms 60% of childhood leukemia.",
      "In AML, median age at diagnosis occurs approximately at 68 years."
    ],
    "answer": ["ALL represents 23% of pediatric cancers."],
    "explanation": "Acute myeloid leukemia (AML) is relatively common in childhood leukemia cases.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Epidemiology of Acute Leukemias",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Secondary AML can arise from the following except:",
    "options": [
      "Myelodysplasia",
      "Myeloproliferative disease",
      "Therapy-related AML",
      "Primary AML",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Primary AML"],
    "explanation": "Secondary AML can arise from conditions like myelodysplasia, myeloproliferative disease, and therapy-related AML, but it is not considered primary AML.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Secondary AML Causes",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "In hemostasis:",
    "options": [
      "Hemostatic process only is involved",
      "Fibrinolytic system is not called to play",
      "There is no balance between procoagulant and anticoagulant",
      "Balance must occur between the procoagulant and anticoagulant proteins",
      "Inhibitors are not required at the site of injury"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Balance must occur between the procoagulant and anticoagulant proteins"
    ],
    "explanation": "Hemostasis requires a delicate balance between procoagulant and anticoagulant proteins to prevent excessive bleeding or clotting.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hemostasis Mechanisms",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Primary hemostatic plug occurs at:",
    "options": [
      "Vascular phase",
      "Plasma phase",
      "Platelet adhesion",
      "Initiation phase",
      "Platelet aggregation"
    ],
    "answer": ["Platelet aggregation"],
    "explanation": "The primary hemostatic plug formation begins with platelet adhesion to the exposed subendothelial matrix at the site of injury.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hemostasis Mechanisms",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The extrinsic tenase complex is:",
    "options": ["TF: VIIIa", "TF: IX", "TF: VII", "TF: Xa", "TF: VIIa"],
    "answer": ["TF: VIIa"],
    "explanation": "The extrinsic tenase complex includes tissue factor (TF) and factor VIIa, which play a role in the extrinsic pathway of coagulation.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Coagulation Pathways",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Fibrinolytic process includes the following proteins except:",
    "options": [
      "Tissue plasminogen activator",
      "Plasminogen",
      "Plasmin",
      "Thrombin",
      "α2-antiplasmin"
    ],
    "answer": ["Thrombin"],
    "explanation": "Thrombin is not part of the fibrinolytic process; it plays a role in the coagulation cascade.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Fibrinolysis",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Molecular genetics discovered by Dameshek include:",
    "options": [
      "JAK2V617F",
      "CALR",
      "Somatic inhibition in JAK2 exon 12",
      "MPL",
      "CSF3R"
    ],
    "answer": ["Somatic inhibition in JAK2 exon 12"],
    "explanation": "JAK2V617F mutation is a significant discovery in the molecular genetics of myeloproliferative neoplasms.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Molecular Genetics in Hematology",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "In the pathogenesis of myeloproliferative neoplasms:",
    "options": [
      "Only one type of JAK family is involved.",
      "Only one type of STAT family is involved.",
      "STAT family includes STAT 1, 2, 3, 4, 5B, and STAT 6.",
      "STAT (Signal Transducer and Activation Transcription).",
      "STAT pathway means Signal Transduction and Activation Transducer."
    ],
    "answer": ["Only one type of JAK family is involved."],
    "explanation": "The pathogenesis of myeloproliferative neoplasms involves various members of the STAT (Signal Transducer and Activation Transcription) family.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Pathogenesis of Myeloproliferative Neoplasms",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "All except are incorrect about Hodgkin Lymphoma:",
    "options": [
      "It is a neoplasm of lymphoid and myeloid tissues.",
      "It originates from the cortex of lymphoid cells.",
      "It is characterized by the presence of Reed-Sternberg cells.",
      "Characteristic immunophenotypes consist of CD20, CD19, and CD79a.",
      "First described by Thomas Hodgkin (1832) using 7 cases."
    ],
    "answer": ["First described by Thomas Hodgkin (1832) using 7 cases."],
    "explanation": "Hodgkin Lymphoma is primarily a neoplasm of lymphoid tissues, not myeloid tissues.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hodgkin Lymphoma Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "About the prevalence of Hodgkin Lymphoma:",
    "options": [
      "Nodular Sclerosis is the most common of all Hodgkin lymphoma",
      "Nodular Sclerosis is least common in prevalent in females",
      "Non-classical forms is more common than classical forms in the older age group.",
      "The Lymphocytes depleted HL is most common in Benin City.",
      "Nodular lymphocyte-predominant is the commonest."
    ],
    "answer": ["Nodular Sclerosis is the most common of all Hodgkin lymphoma"],
    "explanation": "Nodular Sclerosis is more common in females, not least common.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hodgkin Lymphoma Prevalence",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The following are B-cell NHL except:",
    "options": [
      "Hairy cell leukemia",
      "Plasma cell myeloma/plasmacytoma",
      "Extra-nodal marginal zone B-cell NHL",
      "Lymphoma of MALT type of the GIT",
      "Sezary Syndrome"
    ],
    "answer": ["Sezary Syndrome"],
    "explanation": "Hairy cell leukemia is not a B-cell NHL; it is a distinct entity.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "B-cell NHL Classification",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "All are differential diagnoses of Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma except:",
    "options": [
      "Hodgkin's lymphoma.",
      "TB",
      "Castleman disease",
      "Sinus histiocytosis with massive lymphadenopathy (Rosai-Dorfman's disease)",
      "PML RARA proliferative disease"
    ],
    "answer": ["PML RARA proliferative disease"],
    "explanation": "Hodgkin's lymphoma is a distinct entity and should not be considered a differential diagnosis of Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Differential Diagnosis of Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Poor prognostic indices in non-Hodgkin lymphoma include:",
    "options": [
      "Age 60 years at presentation.",
      "Presence of constitutional 'B' symptoms.",
      "Elevated serum LDH.",
      "Low beta2 microglobulin.",
      "High proliferative rate based on ki-67 value."
    ],
    "answer": ["Low beta2 microglobulin."],
    "explanation": "A low beta2 microglobulin level is generally associated with a better prognosis in non-Hodgkin lymphoma.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma Prognostic Factors",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "True about Ann Arbor staging of Lymphomas:",
    "options": [
      "Staging is dissimilar for HL and NHL.",
      "It is the same as Binet staging.",
      "Stage IV in HL is the same as stage 3 HL.",
      "It was first used in 1975/77.",
      "Stage III is the involvement of lymphoid tissues above and below the diaphragm."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Stage III is the involvement of lymphoid tissues above and below the diaphragm."
    ],
    "explanation": "Ann Arbor staging is specific to lymphomas and is different from Binet staging, which is used for chronic lymphocytic leukemia.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Lymphoma Staging",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "One of the following is untrue about the pathogenesis of paraproteinemias:",
    "options": [
      "Enhanced signaling pathways.",
      "Distorted apoptotic mechanisms.",
      "Distorted bone marrow microenvironment.",
      "Evolves from MGUS to SMM to MM.",
      "Cytogenetic abnormalities involving mainly 'even' numbered chromosomes."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Cytogenetic abnormalities involving mainly 'even' numbered chromosomes."
    ],
    "explanation": "Paraproteinemias do not necessarily evolve from MGUS (Monoclonal Gammopathy of Undetermined Significance) to SMM (Smoldering Multiple Myeloma) to MM (Multiple Myeloma). They can remain stable or progress at different rates.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Paraproteinemias Pathogenesis",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following would strongly suggest multiple myeloma?",
    "options": [
      "Severe back pain in a 60-year-old patient with lumbosacral X-Ray showing significant osteophytes.",
      "Osteoporosis of the bony architecture.",
      "Normal WBC count with some rouleau formation.",
      "Elevated gamma-globulin with beta-2 microglobulin of 6ug/L.",
      "Elevated gamma-globulin with beta-2 microglobulin of 6mg/L."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Severe back pain in a 60-year-old patient with lumbosacral X-Ray showing significant osteophytes."
    ],
    "explanation": "Elevated gamma-globulin, particularly with elevated beta-2 microglobulin, is indicative of multiple myeloma.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Multiple Myeloma Diagnosis",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The most appropriate and likely curative treatment for MM in 2023 includes:",
    "options": [
      "Lenalidomide, bortezomib, and dexamethasone combination.",
      "Cyclophosphamide, bortezomib, and dexamethasone.",
      "Daratumomab, bispecific antibody engager with carfilzomib, lenalidomide, and dexamethasone.",
      "Thalidomide, lenalidomide, and dexamethasone.",
      "Lenalidomide and prednisolone."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Daratumomab, bispecific antibody engager with carfilzomib, lenalidomide, and dexamethasone."
    ],
    "explanation": "In recent years, the treatment landscape for multiple myeloma has evolved, and newer treatments, including monoclonal antibodies like daratumumab, have become a part of curative approaches.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Multiple Myeloma Treatment",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Multiple myeloma defining features include all but one:",
    "options": [
      "Elevated calcium.",
      "Presence of anemia.",
      "Chronic renal failure.",
      "Severe osteolytic lesions.",
      "High ESR."
    ],
    "answer": ["High ESR."],
    "explanation": "Multiple myeloma typically presents with features like elevated calcium, anemia, chronic renal failure, and osteolytic lesions, but it is not associated with a high erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR).",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Multiple Myeloma Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The blood film in infectious mononucleosis is reveals:",
    "options": [
      "Circulating megaloblast",
      "Smear cells",
      "Atypical Lymphocytes",
      "Target cells",
      "Neutrophilia"
    ],
    "answer": ["Atypical Lymphocytes"],
    "explanation": "Burkitt lymphoma is typically negative for Bcl-2 protein expression.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Burkitt Lymphoma Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A characteristic clinical feature in infectious mononucleosis is:",
    "options": [
      "Sciatica",
      "Peripheral neuropathy",
      "Pedal oedema",
      "Sore throat",
      "Massive splenomegaly"
    ],
    "answer": ["Sore throat"],
    "explanation": "Hairy cell leukemia primarily affects B cells.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Hairy Cell Leukemia Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "An important laboratory finding in Infectious mononucleosis is:",
    "options": [
      "Positive monospot test",
      "Reduced IgM level, with anti-P specificity",
      "Reduced cold antibody level with anti-H specificity",
      "Reduced EBV capsid antigen titre",
      "Reduced IgG level"
    ],
    "answer": ["Positive monospot test"],
    "explanation": "Chronic myeloid leukemia (CML) is typically associated with the Philadelphia chromosome (Ph chromosome), resulting from the translocation t(9;22)(q34;q11).",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "CML Cytogenetics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which condition is not a cause of generalized lymphadenopathy?",
    "options": [
      "Hodgkins Lymphoma",
      "Hyperthyroidism",
      "Dental Abscess",
      "Toxoplasmosis",
      "Malaria"
    ],
    "answer": ["Dental Abscess"],
    "explanation": "Essential thrombocythemia (ET) is characterized by a persistent and elevated platelet count.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Essential Thrombocythemia Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which is a useful lab investigation for Lymphadenopathy:",
    "options": [
      "Activated partial thromboplastin time",
      "Bone Marrow aspiration",
      "Coagulation screen",
      "Thyroid hormone assay",
      "Lymph node biopsy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Lymph node biopsy"],
    "explanation": "Polycythemia vera (PV) is associated with elevated serum erythropoietin (EPO) levels, as the condition is characterized by the overproduction of red blood cells independently of EPO regulation.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Polycythemia Vera Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Antidote for Heparin",
    "options": [
      "Clexane.",
      "Vitamin K",
      "Protamine sulfate",
      "Fresh frozen plasma",
      "Cryoprecipitate"
    ],
    "answer": ["Protamine sulfate"],
    "explanation": "Myelodysplastic syndromes (MDS) are characterized by cytopenias, which are deficiencies in the number of one or more types of blood cells.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Myelodysplastic Syndromes Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Something about what time a thrombolytic agent should be given",
    "options": [
      "All thrombotic disorders.",
      "6 hours after thrombotic event",
      "12 hours after thrombotic event",
      "24 hours after thrombotic event",
      "Stroke prevention"
    ],
    "answer": ["6 hours after thrombotic event"],
    "explanation": "Acute myeloid leukemia (AML) is characterized by hypercellular bone marrow with a high number of blast cells, which are immature cells of myeloid lineage.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["2nd test med 170"],
    "topics": "Acute Myeloid Leukemia Characteristics",
    "course": "Pathology",
    "subcourse": "Hematology",
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  }
]
